ROY CHANCELLOR

QUALITY + PROCESS ENGINEERING

2014 East Anderson Drive

Phoenix, AZ 85022 Phone: 480.242.6356

E-mail: roychance600@gmail.com
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/roychancellor
Project Portfolio: roychance.wordpress.com

SUMMARY

Accomplished team leader, problem solver, and project finisher who gets results, including coaching and executing Six Sigma projects in multiple facilities in AZ, IL, CT, and Belgium that netted annual savings of \$1M+ over 3 years at Rogers Corp. Passionate shaper of product quality and process excellence with a first-time-right attitude. Ready to apply broad skills in Six Sigma, technical problem solving, and statistical analysis to continue driving quality into Rogers' products across the product cycle.

FIRST TIME RIGHT ATTITUDE

- Co-introduced a new SPC method (PRE-Control)
 that detected spatial variation in ink thickness of EL
 lamps at process setup rather than scrapping whole
 lots at final inspection for out-of-spec brightness
- Led a team that rapidly killed three critical-tolaunch problems for a new EL lamp product, increasing the yield from 10% to 80% before launch while working under intense management scrutiny
- Identified and eliminated the root cause of buckling of micro-ribbon cables before production using a clever mechanical model and experimental validation to upgrade a custom slitting machine

TENACIOUS PROBLEM SOLVER

- Reduced scrap rate by 25 points for EL phosphor
 with annual cost savings of \$124K. Partnered with
 the process owner to install automation that
 removed human variability from the process.
- Eliminated failure-to-bond defects after the launch of a new cell phone keypad lamp. Developed a process to recover one million units-in-process and implemented a permanent solution for future units.
- Eliminated ribbon cable punctures on SEL 3-series relays by redesigning the ribbon cable routing and updating all BOMs within one day to prevent a production stoppage

SHAPER OF QUALITY CULTURE

- Drove Six Sigma upstream into the R&D process by developing strong relationships with R&D managers, enabling focused training and coaching during product development in AZ, IL, and CT
- Trained 75+ Six Sigma Green Belt candidates, including developing course materials and coaching students on projects. Earned high scores in every class for knowledge, clarity, and passion.

PASSIONATE COACH AND MENTOR

- Managed and coached four Six Sigma Black Belts on defect reduction and process improvement projects in multiple factories that saved \$1M+ from 2003-05
- Raised 10+ Green Belts to have highly effective problem-solving skills gained through training, coaching, and mentoring on scrap reduction and process improvement projects. Several went on to be Black Belts and one a Master Black Belt.

KEY SKILLS AND QUALITIES

- Six Sigma
- Rapid Problem Solving
- DOE
- Statistical Process Control
- Electronics Processing
- Coaching & Mentoring
- Risk Reduction (FMEA)
- Relationship Building
- Statistical Analysis
- Finishing Projects
- Humor

EDUCATION

Lean

- Master of Science, Mechanical Engineering Texas A&M University, 1993, GPA 4.0
- Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering Arizona State University, 1991, GPA 3.3
- Advanced Graduate Certificate, Applied Statistics Rochester Institute of Technology, 2004, GPA 4.0
- Post-Baccalaureate Teacher Certification
 Rio Salado College, 2008, GPA 4.0

WORK HISTORY

2015 – Present DIRECTOR OPERATIONS + MASTER TEACHER

Great Hearts Academies, Phoenix, AZ

- Design and deliver highly-interactive mathematics lessons using the Socratic method and high energy
- Organized and led all internal school operations for an 850-student academy including creating the master schedule of classes that solved myriad conflicts and running state-mandated testing (2015-2017)
- Develop honors-level math curricula that are turn-key ready for new teachers to adopt and modify
- Analyze state testing data to drive instructional improvements in core mathematics and English courses

RETURNED TO ARIZONA TO TAKE HYBRID DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS + MASTER MATH TEACHER POSITION

2013 – 2015 MANUFACTURING ENGINEER

Schweitzer Engineering Laboratories, Pullman, WA

- Synthesized requirements from R&D engineers, process engineers, and manufacturing operations to introduce new circuit boards and product assemblies into production and make significant upgrades to existing products
- Solved chronic manufacturing problems on legacy and new products by partnering with product mechanical engineers to design, validate, and release permanent solutions

SABBATICAL FROM TEACHING TO ENGINEERING POSITION IN WASHINGTON

2008 – 2013 MASTER MATHEMATICS TEACHER

Great Hearts Academies, Scottsdale, AZ

- Shaped the honors-level math curriculum during the start-up years of a high-performing charter school
- Designed and delivered highly-interactive mathematics lessons that incorporated the Socratic method

2006 – 2008 MATHEMATICS TEACHER

Scottsdale Unified School District, Scottsdale, AZ

- Created a highly-practical Business Math course that gave at-risk students valuable real-life math skills
- Taught Geometry to high school sophomores using interactive PowerPoint lessons

CAREER CHANGE TO FULL-TIME MATHEMATICS EDUCATION

2005 – 2006 STATISTICIAN

Intel Corporation, Chandler, AZ

- Delivered statistical and technical expertise to microprocessor packaging engineers that included designing experiments, making sense out of complex data, and driving problems to resolution before production:
- Taught multi-week statistical courses to diverse groups engineers, scientists, and technicians with high ratings for clarity, passion, and direct application to students' jobs

2003 – 2005 SIX SIGMA MASTER BLACK BELT

Rogers Corporation, Chandler, AZ

1999 – 2003 SENIOR PROCESS ENGINEER

- Led and coached teams that solved yield and defect problems and implemented corrective/preventative action for high performance circuit board, electroluminescent (EL) lamp, and polyurethane foam products
- Actively drove Six Sigma into the product development cycle to reduce the risk of quality spills before launch

1998 – 1999 MECHANICAL ENGINEER

Orbital Sciences Corporation, Chandler, AZ

- Completed analytical and experimental projects to improve the reliability of electronic packages that control all flight operations of rockets
- Performed fatigue analysis of all production-tested flight units to ensure remaining life was sufficient for flight

1994 – 1998 PROCESS ENGINEER – CABLES

W.L. Gore and Associates, Phoenix, AZ

- Characterized and improved processes for high-volume production of micro-coax and micro-ribbon cable products used in ultrasound medical devices and disk drives
- Created process science that fused mechanical engineering principles with experimental results to kill defects